Finding Aid for the Anaïs Nin Papers, ca. 1910-1977 LSC.2066
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Diaries by Anaïs Nin, 1914-1965; 12.4 Linear Feet
  - Published as Incest. From a Journal of Love. The Unexpurgated Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1932-1934. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich [c1992], .50 linear ft. (10 folders)
    - Diary 45. Novel of Henry - June. Break with Father, 1934 February-July 6 [7].; Holograph. In black leather binding. pp.1-149, pages for 25 April-7 July 1934 are unnumbered. 11.5 × 18 cm. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      "Notes, Henry - Father, Dr. Rank, Rebecca West, London.
      The definite appearance of the demon. "In this journal AN writes that she is pregnant with Henry Miller's child, p.[187].
      Photo of "Emilia" laid in.
      Pages for January 14, 1934 are disbound and laid in between pp.32-33.
      With letters, including 1 from Otto Rank, and cards laid in, notebook and concert programs tipped in, letter from Rebecca West (n.d.) tipped in following page for May 18.
    - Diary 46. Flow. Notes, 1934 July-November.; Holograph. In black leather binding. pp.1-252. 11.5 × 18 cm. pp.188-211 are in a different hand. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      "Otto Rank, Hilaire Hiler, Bone, Louis Andard, Turner, Child-birth, Rebirth."
      Photograph of Dr. Endler, p.252.
      Letters from Rank laid in as well as datebooks and address books.
      Pencil sketch of woman's profile signed "Hiler, Paris, 1934," tipped in front free endpaper.
  - Published as Fire. From A Journal Of Love. The Unexpurgated Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1934-1937. New York: Harcourt, Brace & Company [1995], 1934-1936; .05 linear ft. (6 folders)
    Diaries 47-52.
    - Diary 47. Night and Day. A Story with Two Faces, 1934 November 29-1935 April.; Holograph. In black leather binding. pp.1-261. 11.5 × 18 cm. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      "The Real Play, The Birth of Humor, Dr. Rank: The Problem of Humor." Fire: from a Journal of Love begins in December 1934.
      Datebook and address book tipped in verso of front and back covers.
      Calendar leaves tipped in throughout.
      Photos of Anaïs Nin, pp.100-101, photo of Otto Rank, p.117.
      Letter from Rank laid in.
    - Diary 48. [No title], [1935] April 16-September.; In a 5 year diary in brown leather binding. pp.1-240, jumps from p.136 to p.177, pages following page 250 are unnumbered. 14 × 17.5cm. Holograph. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      Portrait of Joaquin Nin tipped in verso of title page.
      Calendar leaves tipped in and laid in.Various letters and notes laid in.
      "Letter" to Hugh, pp.95-101, "Books read," p. "December 30".
      Business card of Hugh Guiler on p. "November 10."
      "Label 48" covers the number 46 and 49 on title page.
    - Diary 49. [Revolte], 1935 October 6-1936 March 23.; Holograph. In a 5 year diary with embossed green leather binding. Front clasp is missing and leather torn. pp.unnumbered after page 19. 13.5 × 17.5 cm. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Photo of Laura [Archera] following page for April 13.
      Title page missing with AN's note of explanation.
      With photographs of AN and others (unidentified) tipped and laid in.
      With letters, programs, calendar pages and ephemera tipped in.
    - Diary 50. Drifting, 1936 March-August.; Holograph. In a 5 year diary with dark blue leather binding, tooled in gilt and green. Back clasp missing. pp.unnumbered. 13.5 × 17.5 cm. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      New York, S.S. Bremen, Paris.
      "The House of Incest (A Fantasia of Neurosis)" by Anaïs Nin tipped in front free endpaper.
      Note from Gonzalo Moré tipped in page for October 28.
      Photos of AN, Henry Miller, Hugh Guiler and unidentified tipped in as well as letters.
    - Diary 51. Mon Journal. Vive la Dynamite. Nanankepichu, 1936 August 31-December 27.; Holograph. In a 5 year diary in black leather binding with gilt and green decoration. pp.1-56, following pages unnumbered. 13.5 × 17.5 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      "What are you going to do about Alf" by Henry Miller laid in.
      Between pages for May 19-21, 3 typescript pages tipped in re "My little girl not yet born yet."
      Reviews of Tropic of Cancer laid in.
    - Diary 52. Mon Journal and Note Book. Fire, 1936 December 28-1937 March 3.; Holograph. In burgundy leather binding with gilt decoration. pp.1-320. 11.5 × 18 cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Inscribed to AN from her cousin Eduardo, 18 December 1936, on front free endpaper.
  - Published as Nearer The Moon. From a Journal of Love. The Unexpurgated Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1937-1939. New York: Harcourt, Brace & Company [1996], .50 linear ft. (8 folders)
    Diaries 53-60.
    - Diary 53. Journal de Fata Morgana. Un Dieu Qui Rit [?], 1937 March 4-July.; Holograph. In maroon leather binding with gilt decoration. pp.1-305. 11.5 × 18 cm. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Correspondents include Lawrence Durrell and AN's cousin, Eduardo [Sanchez].
      With letters and notes tipped in and laid in.
      With clippings and programs tipped in.
      Also includes clippings of Helba Huara tipped in.
    - Diary 54. C O S M I C. Consumation [sic]. Collective. Self-Abnegation. Le Monde. Isolation Circles, 1937 July 12-September.; Holograph. With green paper cover, lacking back cover. pp.1-238, [pp.1-225], then reverts to 197-239. 22.5 × 27.5 cm. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Beginning, "Not the small notebook I could hide."
      Correspondents include Thurema, Esther Harding, Patrick Evans, Gonzalo Moré.
      Partial index, p.238.
      Letters and poems laid in, and a copy of AN's letter to Djuna Barnes.
    - Diary 55. Mon Journal and Note Book. Maya, 1937 September-November 8.; Holograph. In brown leather binding with gilt edges. Stamped "A.N." on upper left corner of front cover. pp.1-181. 14.5 × 20.5 cm. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Beginning, "I am not a pathological liar." re Lawrence Durrell, Henry Miller, Gonzalo Moré.
      Prospectus for publication of AN's diary by Henry Miller tipped in front endpaper.
      With list of subscribers to diary on front endpaper.
      List of writings preceding page 1.
    - Diary 56. Mon Journal. 30 Quai de Passy, Paris 16me. (Parenthesis), 1937 November.; Holograph. Bound in burgundy leather. pp.1-356, 361. Pages 357-360 have been cut out. 10.5 × 17.5 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Letter of rejection from International Literature (T. Rokotov), 15 November 1937, laid in front endpaper.
      "Quotations from books read 1920 Richmond Hill" with excerpts from various books copied, usually with comments by AN throughout and afterwards, pp.1-189.
      Beginning of "Diary" on p.190, "No more diary volumes on hand, I found this dusty little book among the books."
      Diary 56 is written in a datebook for 1921.
      Postcards and typescript pages have been tipped in.
    - Diary 57. Les Mots Flottants. Mon Journal, 1937 December 12-1938 January, March.; Holograph. pp.1-146. 14.5 × 22.5 cm. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Signed Henry Miller on front flyleaf with AN's note, "This was the dummy of the the [sic] Journal I Henry intended to publish. I only collected 2000 frs. The plan failed."
      Proof copy of "The paper Womb" by AN tipped in, pp.102-103.
      Ephemera, postcards, calendar pages, excerpts of letters from Gonzalo Moré, concert programs for Joaquin Nin-Culmell tipped in.
      Reprint of "Un Etre Etoilique" by HM tipped in.
    - Diary 58. Nearer the Moon. Mon Journal, 1938 March-September.; Holograph. In green leather binding. Back clasp missing. pp.1-340 with additional unnumbered pages. Page numbers 105-112 are skipped. 12 × 17.5cm. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Photos of AN on houseboat, "La Belle Aurore," and Hugh Guiler.
      Letter from Henghes, 7 Wentworth Studios, Manresa Road, London.
      With letters, clippings, flyers, photos, calendar and datebook leaves tipped and laid in.
      2pp. taped together with letter from Henry Miller tucked in between, before pp.[345-346].
    - Diary 59. Book of My Metamorphoses. Book of Maya, 1938 December-1939 January.; Holograph. In black cloth binding with Modern Alchemy, Dorothy Fisk, Faber & Faber on the spine [dummy volume]. pp.1-96, every other page is numbered. 14 × 21 cm. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      With flyers, clippings, typescript pages laid in.
    - Diary 60. Mon Journal, 1939 January-April.; Holograph. In brown leather binding. Hinge has pulled away from the binding. Split in leather, left front cover. Back clasp missing. pp.1-296, followed by unnumbered pages. 12.5 × 17.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      "La Tubereuse aux Muqueuses," Pleureuses," "Peniche Book started March 17." Death of AN's father, pp.52-.
      Letters and ephemera tipped in.
      Photo of AN, Barcelona 1913, tipped in verso of frontcover.
      Horoscope of Otto Rank, in manuscript, then covered by typewritten sheets tipped in, followed by letter from Henry Miller (blue ink) and Conrad Moricand(?) (black ink) tipped in, pp.[298]-[312].
  - Diaries by Anaïs Nin, 1939-1965; 9.0 lin ft. (106 folders)
    Diaries 61-[111].
    - Diary 61. [No title], 1939 June-October.; Holograph. In yellow cloth binding with Alexander Pope, Edith Sitwell, Faber & Faber stamped on the spine [dummy volume]. pp.1-185. 14.5 × 22.5 cm. Many of the pages are uncut with letters, some in french, laid in. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      With inscription to "..the great diarist Anaïs Nin" from "Larry" [Durrell].
      Correspondents include Henry Miller, Conrad Moricand, Hugh Guiler.
      Photos and clippings tipped in.
      Photo of AN as a child tipped in verso of rear cover.
      With astrological charts for Joaquin and AN.
    - Diary 62. Kenilworth & Death of the Mother. Mon Journal, 1939 October-1940 November.; Holograph. Bound in red cloth. pp.1-[654]. 14 × 22.5 cm. Letters in envelopes are tipped in following unnumbered pages. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Photos of Caresse Crosby, Henry Miller, Salvador Dali, the Earl of Kenilworth, AN with Mr. & Mrs. Ruttner, Jimmy Sternes.
      "Diacritical & historical materialism," pp.1-21.
      With letters from Henry Miller, John, the Earl of Kenilworth, Hugo, postcards, pocket calendar, clippings.
      With programs forperformances for the Katherine Dunham Dance Group and Joaquin Nin-Culmell.
      Catalog card for Winter of Artifice tipped in verso of front cover.
    - Diary 63. Mon Journal. House of Death & Escape, 1940 December 8-1941 June.; Holograph. In red cloth binding with abstract design on paper pasted on cover. pp.1-[374]. Index, pp.364-[375]. 14.5 × 23 cm. pp.83-84, 92-95 and 128-130 are in a different hand. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Extracts from The Journal of Albion Moonlight by Kenneth Patchen.
      Correspondents include Caresse Crosby, Luise Rainer, Henry Miller's father.
      Photos of AN, pp.288-290. Sketch of AN by Gonzalo Moré (p.232).
      pp.128-130 comment on the diaries.
      "Books read," p.[370].
      Clipping of Virginia Woolf's suicide note, p.216 and sketches by Gonzalo Moré.
      Letters tipped and laid in. Drawings, ephemera tipped and laid in.
      [Negative available of p.288.]
    - Diary 64. Inter-Mezzo. Mon Journal, 1941 July-August 9.; Holograph. With green leather binding. pp.1-188. 13 × 18.5 cm. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      "Provincetown," "Book of Climaterics," "Edward Graëffe," "Siegfried."
      Photographs (unidentified- Gonzalo Moré? ) tipped in.
      Portions of this diary are in Spanish.
    - Diary 65. Birth of the Press, 1941 November 4-1942 October 24.; Holograph. pp.1-366, index and "Books read" follow, unnumbered. 14 × 20.5 cm. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      In a datebook for 1936 with black leather binding with dustjacket for Winter of Artifice pasted on the cover.
      With horoscope in AN's hand for Edward Graëffe and "Pisces year ahead" by Edward Levi laid in front endpaper.
      Sketches by Gonzalo Moré, clippings of graphic war images.
      With postcard from Edward Graëffe, AN's letter (?) to Gonzalo (16pp. in Spanish), calendar of events in AN's life (unnumbered pages).
      With photos of AN at her press, pp.[ 376]-[382] and Nin display at Argus Bookshop, announcement for Ian Hugo exhibit at the New School for Social Research, clippings, drawings tipped in, prospectus for Winter of Artifice, pp.210-212.
    - Diary 66. Mon Journal. A la Recherche des Jeux Perdus with Martha Jaeger, 1942 October 27-1943 October 3.; Holograph. Bound in blue/grey cloth binding with The Woolcott Reader, The Viking press on the spine [dummy volume]. pp.1-1218. 13.5 × 22 cm. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      List of books read follows numbered pages.
      "Winter of Artifice," p.178, "American infantilism," p.180.
      Fashion clippings, pp.185-191, 315-316, "Date Book," pp.495-499, photo, p.1218, unidentified.
      With sketches of AN by Gonzalo Moré, letters from Henry Miller, card with marriage proposal from Hugh Guiler (August 15, 1922), p.154.
      With AN's description of her dreams.
      Second pages 1118-1130, penciled note by AN, "copied."
      With drawings, letters, horoscopes, ephemera, clippings tipped and laid in.
      Pages are inconsistently numbered as follows: pp.1-143, 134-350, 331-359, 370-1119, 112-1218.
    - Diary 67. [No title], 1943 October-1944 March.; Holograph. Written in datebook for 1944 with red cloth binding. Pages unnumbered. 9 × 15 cm. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Contains letters, including some from Henry Miller, Christmas list and expenses, notes re psychoanalysis and the detective story, p. "Oct. 27."
      Listing of wardrobe, p. "Jan. 26-30."
      With names and addresses and household "To do" lists.
      With letters and weekly calendar leaves tipped and laid in.
    - Diary 68. Mon Journal, 1944 April 15 [&] May-1945 November.; Holograph. Much of this journal written on rice paper interspersed with letters. In a laminate pink cover. pp.1-502. 25 × 30.5 cm. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      "Under a Glass Bell, Harry, Chinchilito Lanny, Writing of "This Hunger ... ," William Pinckard, Pablo, David Moore, Discovery of Joy."
      Includes letters, writings, horoscopes, Rorschach analyses, ephemera, clippings and photos of Hugh Guiler and AN.
      AN analyzes various people throughout.
      With astrological chart for Lanny [Baldwin], engraving by Ian Hugo, a water color signed "W.P., 1945."
    - Diary 69. Mon Journal: The Transparent Child, 1945 November-1946 May.; pp.unnumbered. 19 × 24.5 cm. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Much of this volume concerns Gore Vidal with photos of GV, dustjacket of Williwaw inscribed to AN, GV's horoscope.
      "Within the intricate" by GV, p. "180th day," "Moving pictures" by GV, p. "245th day," letter and "Earlier dream" by GV laid in between p. " 252nd day-253rd day."
      With loose pages from After the Lost Generation by John W. Aldridge which includes critiques of works by GV, Paul Bowles, Truman Capote & Frederick Buechner.
      With photographs, letters, ephemera, clippings tipped and laid in.
      With "A love scene from In a Yellow Wood for the maker of it -- Gore Vidal," 10pp., holograph manuscript in pencil, laid in, removed from pocket on verso of back cover.
      Manila envelope taped onto page following December 31 is empty.
    - Diary [70]. [No title], 1946.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[172b]. Some pages numbered by AN. With loose journal pages taped to sheets of paper. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Gore Vidal, Hugh Guiler, Bill Burford, Wallace Fowlie, John Crowe Ransome, Jean Varda [Yanko] and others.
      Many letters concern Ladders of Fire, including letters protesting Herbert Lyon's review in the New York Times Book Review.
      Includes some letters from 1947. "Garden of Eden"begins on p.[58].
      With a centennial menu from Antoine's Restaurant, New Orleans.
    - Diary [71]. 1947 - I Un Etre Etoilique. Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1947 January.; Looseleaf. Written on tissue paper with heavier stock backing most pages. Portions are bound with tape. pp.[1]-[1140]. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Gore Vidal, Hugh Guiler and others.
      Daily calendar pages are interspersed.
      (folder 1 of 2)
    - Diary [71]. 1947 - I Un Etre Etoilique. Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1947 January.; Looseleaf. Portions are bound with tape. pp.[141]-[305]. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Henry Rago, Mary Caroline Richards, Merle Armitage, Lawrence Clark Powell, Hugh Guiler, Herbert West, Lila Rosenblum and others.
      With note to AN from Gore Vidal, p.[169], T.[Theodore] Weiss critique, "Kenneth Patchen and Chaos as Vision," p.[187].
      Some daily calendar pages are interspersed.
      (folder 2 of 2)
    - Diary [72]. 1947 - II, 1947 April (includes some dates from 1948).; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[137]. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Gore Vidal, Reginald Pole, Lila Rosenblum and others.
      With AN's letters to Rupert Pole.
      With "Lawrence's Quarrel with Freud" by Frederick J. Hoffman from Quarterly Review of Literature, pp.[279]-287.
      Also includes postcards from the American Southwest, photos of AN in New Orleans, AN and Rupert Pole in Taos (negatives available), maps and itinerary for AN's cross country trip with Rupert Pole.
    - Diary [73]. 1948 - I, Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[111]. Journal pages numbered 1-21. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from William Pinckard, William Burford, AN's letters to Rupert Pole.
      With pocket calendar for 1948, 2 fragments of letters from Gore Vidal, ephemera, envelope with key.
      Photo of Rupert Pole, p.[11] and William Pinckard, p.[98], negative available.
    - Diary [74] 1948 - II. Mon Journal, 1948 May 18-July.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[146]. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Includes AN's letters to Rupert Pole and letters to AN from Hugh Guiler.
      Photo of Rupert Pole, p.[14] verso of page numbered 26 (negative available).
    - Diary [74] 1948 - II. Mon Journal, 1948 May 18-July.; Looseleaf. pp.[114]-[185]. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Postcards from Guatemala, Mexico and the American Southwest mounted on blank pages.
    - Diary [75]. [No title], 1949.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[120]. Some pages have tape residue with fragments of letters attached. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Includes writings interspersed with letters and ephemera.
      With AN's letters to Rupert Pole and letters to AN from Hugh Guiler.
      Includes AN's "Two Chambered Heart. 72," San Francisco, 20 October 1949, beginning with the death of her father, written on Japanese fanfold paper.
    - Diary [75]. [No title], 1949.; Looseleaf. pp.[121]-[283]. Some pages have tape residue with fragments of letters attached. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Lawrence Clark Powell (UCLA Library) and others and AN's letters to Rupert Pole.
    - Diary [76]. [No title], 1950.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[134]. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Includes AN's letters to Rupert Pole and Hugh Guiler (Ian Hugo).
      With letters from Christopher Isherwood (8 August), p.[66], John Crowe Ranson (6 July), p.[64], and Irene Selznick (2 June), p.[40].
    - Diary [77]. [No title], 1951.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[73]. Written on Japanese fanfold paper cut into folded pages. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      "The Tree of Life" by AN, pp.1-141, 7 December 1951.
      (folder 1 of 3)
    - Diary [77]. [No title], 1951.; Looseleaf. pp.[74]-[328]. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Includes AN's letters to Rupert Pole and her writings re her relationship with Rupert.
      With letters from Hugh Guiler and Max Geismar.
      With photos of Hugh Guiler in Mexico, p.[241-a], negatives available.
      (folder 2 of 3)
    - Diary [77]. [No title], 1951.; Looseleaf. pp.[329]-[426]. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, James Laughlin, Lila Rosenblum, Max Pfeffer and various publishers.
      With unsigned carbon of letter to Helen and Lloyd Wright, pp.[379]-[380].
      With AN's notes, photos and postcards of a trip to Mexico with Rupert.
      (folder 3 of 3)
    - Diary [78]. 1952 - I, 1952 May-August.; Looseleaf. pp.[ [1]-[165]. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Kathryn Winslow, James Herlihy ("Jim"), Felix Pollak, Hugh Guiler, Robert Duncan and AN's writings re her life with Rupert Pole.
      With clippings on drama, dance and architecture (Frank Lloyd Wright), pp.[65]-[67].
    - Diary [78]. 1952 - I, 1952 May-August.; Looseleaf. pp.[166]-[420]. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Rupert Pole, Hugh Guiler, Felix Pollak, James Laughlin, Gore Vidal, p.[342], James Herlihy, Stanley Kaufman.
    - Diary [79]. 1952 - II, Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[221]. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Robert Duncan, James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, Hugh Guiler, Kathryn Winslow, Lila Rosenblum, James Laughlin, Maxwell Geismar, Kurt Wolff, Louis and Bebe Barron and others.
    - Diary [79]. 1952 - II, Looseleaf. pp.[221]-[436]. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from James Herlily, Rupert Pole, Hugh Guiler, Felix Pollak, Kimon Friar, Maxwell Geismar.
      With transcript of radio interview with AN on KFAC, Los Angeles, 29 October 1952.
    - Diary [79]. 1952 - II, Looseleaf. pp.[437]-[627]. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, Hugh Guiler, Felix Pollak, John Aldridge, Lila Rosenblum,various publishers.
    - Diary [80]. 1953 - I, pp.[1]-[191]. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Includes AN's letters to Rupert Pole, letters from James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, various publishers.
      With cover of the The Antioch Review (Summer 1953), and a prospectus for A Spy in the House of Love.
    - Diary [80]. 1953 - I, Looseleaf. pp.[192]-[359]. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, Maxwell Geismar.
      With AN's observations on RP, Frank Lloyd Wright and Lloyd Wright, pp.[193]-[207] and AN's "On Maxwell Geismar," beginning on p.[269].
      With clipping of MG's review of The Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone by Tennessee Williams.
    - Diary [80]. 1953 - I, Looseleaf. pp.[360]-[503]. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, Maxwell Geismr, AN's letters to RP.
      With AN's observations on RP, Frank Lloyd Wright and Lloyd Wright.
      Letter from Rupert Pole written on a program for the Lester Horton Dance Theatre.
      With dustjacket for A Spy in the House of Love.
    - Diary [81]. 1953 - II, Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[202]. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Ian Hugo (Hugh Guiler), Gavin Lambert, p.[6], Maxwell Geismar, F. Macht, note from Kimon Friar.
      With ephemera and clippings, including a program for Truman Capote's The Grass Harp at Circle in the Square and a menu from "Caffee."
    - Diary [81]. 1953 - II, Looseleaf. pp.[203]-[375]. (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Stanley Mills Haggart, Lila Rosenblum.
      With clipped article, "Preservation of Innocence" by James Baldwin.
      With clippings and ephemera, including program for Martha Graham Dance Company.
      With dustjacket for Rebels and Ancestors by Maxwell Geismar.
    - Diary [82]. 1954 - [I], Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[218]. (Box 26, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, Wallace Fowlie (5 May), Edmund Wilson (4 July), Felix Pollak.
      Photos of RP in Acapulco, pp.[105]-[106].
      Photo of AN's mother, p.[1] on memorial card.
      AN's notes re her participation in a Kenneth Anger film as "Miss Moonlight," accompanying photos are missing.
      Prospectus for A Spy in the House of Love.
      AN's "blurb" for Val Telberg exhibition, Hacker Gallery, New York.
      Newspaper clipping with photo of AN, Rupert Pole and Reginald Pole being evacuated after a fire.
    - Diary [82]. 1954 - [I], Looseleaf. pp.[219]-[465]. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from James Herlihy, Rupert Pole, photocopies of letters from her brother, Joaquin Nin-Culmell.
      With AN's letters to Rupert Pole and Hugh Guiler.
      AN's horoscope, p.[304].